<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Jeff Kulas</title>
    <link>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Jeff Kulas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 16:17:17 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jeffkulas.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Balance Nature Humanity</title>
      <link>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/industry-balance-nature-humanity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 16:17:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/industry-balance-nature-humanity/</guid>
      <description>Semi-checked-capitalistic industry has made life better for millions of people who have been raised out of poverty and enjoy a more comfortable, easier life. Yet, some people still don’t have adequate food, housing or security. The saying capitalism raises all boats is simply not correct. Simultaneously, some industries have ravaged the environment, poisoning the air, water and land and some directly poison people.
We eat food that really isn’t that good for us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passion</title>
      <link>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/passion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 23:41:11 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/passion/</guid>
      <description>I’ve got a passion. It&amp;rsquo;s called peace.
I believe that increasing global computation capacity is a good thing. Computation can be used to simulate and model reality in order to try to predict outcomes given sets of choices available and conditions that may or may not be under our control.
If we propose something we can model it and see what happens in a variety of configurations and conditions. Does it have the desired outcome?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Knowledge Gain</title>
      <link>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/automated-knowledge-gain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 08:44:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/automated-knowledge-gain/</guid>
      <description>Do we need artificial general intelligence in order to automate knowledge gain? I&amp;rsquo;m not sure we do. If we can automate knowledge gain at a reasonable cost we can discover new materials, new parts, new processes, new designs and new methods. We can also learn about existing systems like the biology that makes us well.. us.
If we simulate reality inside of a computer we can try many, many combinations of ways of affecting that model in a computer and then if something looks promising we can try to produce that thing in the physical world and see how it works there versus in a simulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agency &amp; Scarcity</title>
      <link>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/agency-and-scarcity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 10:34:27 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/agency-and-scarcity/</guid>
      <description>While on a nice week long vacation with my family I had the opportunity to think a little more than I often can. My normal fleeting thoughts of our human condition bounced around as I considered automation and the rate of technological change due to exponential knowledge gain. Heathcare systems and guaranteed income are often part of this jumble of thoughts. I seemed to meander into the human aspect this time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo</title>
      <link>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 21:24:31 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jeffkulas.com/posts/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>It was time for a site refresh&amp;hellip;  jeffkulas.com was way out of date .. my last post was from 2012! my site did not support TLS octopress was kind of weird to me since I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar with ruby  I decided to switch over to github pages and looked for a static site generator to replace octopress and I found Hugo.
First Impression  hugo is fast live reload is really nice and just works adding and customizing themes is easy playing around with a theme is nice as it helps me understand some of hugo&amp;rsquo;s concepts  So far so good.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>